

Lead Full Stack Developer with more than 2 year of experience in ASP.NET. Throughout my 2 year plus career as a software developer. I have focused on developing scalable and well-documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with project independently. I worked as a freelancer and also worked on the government project Like for BCIL ministry of agriculture, NCTE ministry of Education and Earned the .NET Badge on LinkedIn. and also expert in finding and resolving bug on run time.

#### Skills

Skill Summary	
ASP.NET III Net Programming-C#.Net III Net Framework III Sql Server III JavaScript III Angular JS III ASP.NET Web API	Ш
Amazon API Gateway III ASP.NET Core III SQL III Azure Virtual Machine III CSS III HTML 5 III Entity Framework	ıl
Entity Framework Core III Project Management Team Leader Project Monitoring and Control	

#### Work Experience

#### Cognizant Experience

CDE-PDP - H&T Training | Jr. Software Engineer - 2 Months (Jan 2022 - Mar 2022)

#### Project Description

Airline Booking Project is developed during the time of H&T Training in which two different role exists. Admin or User. User can search for flight, book the flight and cancel the booking. Admin can add the new flights, there schedules and manage the role or able to see all the booking that is registered in the software. User can search their bookings by PNR no.

#### Roles & Responsibilities

Role: Design and Developed the frontend in Angular JS, Optimize the Code, write the TDD level test cases, Design and Developed the backend, APIs in Asp.net Core Web APIs with swagger documentation, write unit test cases, apply the layered approach, make the API gateway using ocelot, merge the Rest API end points, Host the angular project and APIs on Azure web service, do the Azure API management, deploy the code on Azure VM, and do use of Azure SQL server and SQL databases. Responsibilities: Implementation, Migration, Merging and handling of Modules

#### Skills used for CDE -PDP - H&T Training

ASP.NET III	.Net Progra	amming-C#.Net III	.Net Frame	work III Sql	Server III	JavaScript	Angular JS	الد	ASP.NET Web API III
Amazon API Gate	way 📶	ASP.NET Core	SQLIl	Azure Virtual M	1achine 📶	CSS .III	HTML5 all	Entity	Framework III
Entity Framework	Core III	Project Management							

#### Other Experience

Store Pharmacy Software | Jr. Software Developer - 5 Months (Jul-2019 - Dec 2019)

#### Project Description

Design and Develop using Asp Web forms, jQuery, JavaScript, crystal reports, API. when I worked as trainee in the Steward Healthcare Pvt. Ltd. The Software is based on the hospital Store to reduce the time for taking medicine form the hospital to the patient room, and maintain the records of every patient. The patient Nurse will make the indent of the medicine and other stuffs, and submit in the software, all the things is linked with the patient UHID and interlink with the hospital software.

#### Roles & Responsibilities

Role: Develop all the modules, Preparing of the presentation and Approval from the Company director, interlink and Migrate the software with the Hospital UHID, and merging of Billing process. Develop all the web Form, Create Designs, Patterns and Structures, Design and maintain Database. Deployment on IIS Key Responsibilities:- Deployment of software on QA server for testing and resolving of bugs and modified all the other points and maintaining the Database. Deployment and maintaining of Code on Live Server

### 

ASP.NET III Net Programming-C#.Net III Net Framework III Sql Server III Sql Server III SQL III CSS III HTML 5 IIII

Project Management Team Leader Project Monitoring and Control

Laboratory Information System | Jr. Software Developer - 1 Year & 2 Months (Jan-2020 - Mar 2021)

### ☐ Project Description

The project is based on the laboratory information system. The work flow is start from the registration of the patient including the test which he/she has to be done, then the lab take the sample from him/her. The machine is interface with the software so that the result or report is generated according to the sample.

### Roles & Responsibilities

My main role is to develop the new modules and the resolve the bug on the run time. giving support to the client take the requirement from him and work on it to fulfillment the requirement. Mainly there is the different report generation according to the client or making of the report using crystal reports or HIQPDF. Applying of the triggers and making views in database from the different tables to show on frontend or work on the accounts ledger transaction reports. Merging different payment gateways at one time in the LIS.

### DISSIBLE Skills used for Laboratory Information System

ASP.NET III Net Programming-C#.Net III Net Framework III Sql Server III Sql Server III SQL III CSS III HTML 5 III

NCS-TCP Portal | Software Developer - 6 Months (Apr-2021 - Sep 2021)

### Project Description

This is the Govt project for Biotech consortium India limited named NCS-TCP( National Certification System for tissue Culture raised Plants). In this System the different recognition register himself and then investigation is done for the generate samples and meeting is scheduled after testing of the samples given by the recognition Center between the members of NCS to give approval to him for sale of their seeds and grow plants. According to the meeting approval the certification is provided to the Recognition centers for plants Like Potato, Tomato, Beans.

### Roles & Responsibilities

Responsibility is to do fully dynamic the portal like the meeting part is done manually. Design and Developed the PMEC Meeting Module, Bulk Printing of Certification. Build the auto mail and SMS service Auto approval services, Maintaining of QA and LIVE server. Do the Deployment of Code on QA and Live Server. Done the upgradation of the Live server. Give Support to the BCIL regarding any issue and resolve queries. Do contact with the NIC for the Payment related issue. Provide Application Level training to BCIL members.

### DO Skills used for NCS-TCP Portal

ASP.NET III Net Programming-C#.Net III Net Framework III Sql Server III Sql Server III SQL III CSS III HTML 5 IIII

Entity Framework III Project Management Team Leader Project Monitoring and Control

# Career Highlights

Achievement: Merging of four Payment gateway at one time for single client. Award for develop of Store module Software as trainee.

# Education

# Graduation

